this morning we're going to make a strawberry
gelato strawberries are in season they're
looking delicious it's really easy to do
this so let's just get on and make [Music]
it yeah strawberries they're in season now so
they're all looking really nice um I mean you
know this is Walmart so if strawberries are
good in Walmart then they're good everywhere
so for this we're going to take 200 g of
strawberries with 115 g of sugar and 55
G of corn syrup corn syrup or glucose syrup
whatever you want so first thing I'm going
to do cut stalks off the strawberries cut
them into small pieces and get them in this
pan with our strawberries all cut
up I just cut these into quarters
but the smaller they are the quicker they'll
be cooked so we've got those in the pan here we
are simply going to add all of our sugar this
is all of the sugar in this ice cream and 55
G of our corn syrup try and be accurate for this
55 G what 1/4 cup 56 G close enough that is now
going to go on the hob so with the heat on we're
just going to swirl this around a little bit and
leave those strawberries to break down into a
really rich sauce it's going to take 10 minutes
maybe 15 minutes after a few minutes on high
temperature it will start to look like this
and this is strawberries are releasing the
water mixing with the sugar creating a syrup
and we can just continually stir this up get
these strawberries really really broken down
they break down this this process of macerating
which is a way of making them really really soft
and a boosting sweetness after about 10 minutes
when you can lift a strawberry up and squish it
against the side and it just starts to break up
into nothing these are ready to process they've
released all this water it's mixed in with the
sugars created this thick syrup it's foaming and
Rising because of the evat of water is starting
to create an invert syrup so the inclusion of
corn syrup in this is to stop any sugar crystals
recrystallizing down the line so this is why you
get a really lovely texture with this gelato
apparently some people moan about how I say
gelato so for those people Gelato at this stage
let's just turn the heat off we're going to let
this cool down so we want this to cool down
somewhat because we're going to start adding
it into our Dairy so smell of this strawberry
syrup in here is incredible we're going to lead
the strawberry pieces in so what we can do is
get our Dairy ready this is pretty simple you
can substitute this for dairyfree milk and cream
if you want to just be careful with the cream cuz
some of it just tastes like crap um don't make
this taste like strawberry and coconut just buy
one that that doesn't taste like coconut please
anyway 195 G of 2% milk way too much and on top
of that we're going to use 386 G of 33% whipping
cream some of you might wonder why we're not using
a lot of milk in this recipe and that is simply
because the strawberries are full of water I mean
absolutely loaded so of that 200 G of strawberries
probably 190 G of that is water so we've got our
milk and our cream in here we are going to put
that into there but the one last thing we need
to do is to add our milk powder if you're going
to use a stabilizer add it into here if you're
not then don't I'm going to I'm going to use a
stabilizer this is uh an off-the-shelf generic
mix and and if you want to use a stabilizer
just use 1.2 g into the milk powder Stir It
Up you can use gu gum zanam gum whatever you
can use a combination blend if you're really
into stabilizers then you know use your 422 blend
you don't really need an Ulf fire in this but you
can do if you want to milk powder is now going to
go into our Dairy and we are going to get a bigger
whisk and stir that together and now we are going
to add in our strawberries we're going to do the
we're going to do this while we continue to
whisk nice and slow get all of that syrup at
the bottom we want every little ounce that's
remaining if you didn't use a stabilizer you
can put this straight in the fridge if you use a
stabilizer that is cold process you can put this
straight in the fridge if you use a stabilizer
that is hot process like I do we need to heat it
back up to 85c so let's do that so just keep
stirring until you get up to 85c you need to
stir it quite well a little bits of strawberry
will kind of get stuck to the pan otherwise but
now we're up to temperature we can simply
turn the heat off and take it off the hole
that's heated up now you actually don't
need a stabilizer for this cuz the invert
sugar will do quite a lot for this recipe
so if you use stabilizers just give it a
Miss on this one I I use them because a lot
of people that watch this channel like the
science side of it but the invert sugar will
help stabilize Ice Crystal formation so it's
not really essential for this but what we can do
now that it is heated up is get everything into a
bowl and we're going to chill it down get off
sometime later this year we're going to get
that in the fridge to chill down it's going
to take you know 3 or 4 hours something like
that so after 3 or 4 hours and the base is
completely chilled down we're going to take
it out of the fridge and put it in a blender
this stage isn't really necessary but I don't
like huge lumps of fruit in my ice cream
because they just go icy there's no room
way to avoid that so we pulse this up just
for a minute 30 seconds to a minute to break
up those any remaining lumps of fruit and we can
just pour it straight in our ice cream machine
which is pre-chilled for 10 minutes and get it
churning after that stage is complete I think
this took about 12 or 15 minutes in my machine
we just start loading up the tubs Walmart special
tubs these are less than a dollar I love these
things plus it's a bit better for the environment
keep using cardboard containers but hey I still
like those it's what ice cream comes in anyway
load up the tubs and we can start dishing up one
thing I did notice is actually the original recipe
had a little bit too much milk powder so I've
adjusted it for this so you you get the best
result but as you can see super smooth incredibly
delicious strawberry gelatte glorious easy
strawberry ice cream I rued it as this is gelato
gelato normally has you know between 18 and 21
or even 22% sugar I actually reduced this down a
little bit because I like to taste the strawberry
flavor coming through a bit more than the sugar
so with that in mind you will need to take this
out of the freezer just for a few minutes just to
let it soften up enough to scoop it I also think
it would benefit based on the scooping I think it
would benefit from slightly less skin milk powder
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to adjust the
video to put the correct amount that I think would
be perfect for this recipe when you want to make
it so let's just try and see what it tastes like
[Music] it's delicious the corn syrup or if you're
going to use glucose glucose invert sugar whatever
it is you want to use uh for that part of the
recipe it creates this super kind of smooth
effect really creamy but this is delicious
and the strawberry flavor is really nice
Summer's nearly here this will be perfect in
an ice cream cone use this recipe in your ice
cream machine in your Ninja creamy whatever
it's oh it's incredible anyway I hope you
like this dropping ice cream I hope you like
this super easy strawberry gelato video recipe
do give it a try let me know if you do what
you think and I'll see you next week [Music]